

# Evgeniy Babiychuk

#### **Expert React and React Native Developer**

#### SUMMARY

I am a web and mobile developer with 8 years of experience, specializing in React and React Native. Throughout my career, I have successfully created and enhanced numerous web and mobile apps, working across various industries including ecommerce, social media platforms, blockchain, data visualizations, and SaaS projects. I am always eager to explore new technologies and seek out fresh opportunities in this field. Before starting work on a project, I think

ahead how it should be in the end, introducing myself as a consumer of the project. I excel at working collaboratively to solve complex problems and enjoy being part of a team.

#### EDUCATION

2015-2017

# Master's degree in Software Engineering

National Aviation University (Institute Of Computer Information Technologies) - full-time education

2008 - 2012

# Software Development - Junior Specialist

College Of Information Technology And Land Management

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Jun 2023 - Feb 2024

## Frontend Developer

#### Sixpack Motors

Replacement and accessories for all US cars, car import, sales, mfk, workshop, preparation, tuning

My Role:

I've built the frontend o this website -

#### https://www.sixpackmotors.ch/

Required skills: React, NextJS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, LESS, SASS

Feb 2023 - Dec 2023

# Full Stack Developer

#### SimpleShowing

simpleshowing is the new way to buy or sell a home. Users can buy with their team of licensed agents, and save up to \$15,000. sell for only a 1% listing fee.

My Role:

I've built both frontend and backend of the web site -

#### https://www.simpleshowing.com/

Required skills: React, Node.JS

Mar 2022 - Apr 2023

# Full Stack Developer

#### **SAYU**

golf equipment online from complete golfer, huge savings on all the top brands at lowest uk price guaranteed plus free next day uk delivery.

My Role:

I've built both frontend and backend of the website -

https://www.completegolfer.co.uk/

Required skills: Javascrpit, Co-PHP

June 2020 - August 2021

## Frontend Developer

#### Merehead

Merehead is an outsourcing company, that mainly focuses on developing fintech and blockchain solutions.

My Role:

- 1. Developing user-facing features using React.js
- -Setup applications from scratch.
- -Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use
- -Translating designs and wireframes into high-quality code
- -Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers
- -Deploying code to staging/production
- 2. Participation in the development of 6 projects in the direction of marketplace, blockchain, social network project, and a small private site

Required skills: Typescript, React, React-router, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Redux-Saga, Git, ESlint, WebSocket, Restful APIs, Postman, React Hooks, Axios, Styled Components, Stripe, i18next

July 2019 - January 2020

# Frontend Developer

#### Jerelia

Zherelia is a large-scale network company that provides natural cosmetics, innovative eco-cleaning products for the home, accessories, vitamins, complex body cleansing programs, herbal preparations for health from Ukraine.

My Role:

I've built a shopping mall website for this company. -

#### https://jerelia.com/

My role is to build the frontend and integrate backend.

Required skills: ReactJS, NodeJS

September 2016 - June 2017

# Frontend Developer

#### Energorynok

Energorynok is a state-owned company founded in 2000 by the state in person of the Cabinet of Ministers of Ukraine and is a Party to the Agreement between the members of the Wholesale Electricity Market of Ukraine.

My Role:

I've built 2 website for this company

https://www.oree.com.ua/

https://www.gpee.com.ua/

**Required skills:** Javascript, Google map service, iCheck, ChartJS, Oracle DB, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap

Figma

June 2017 - March 2019

## Frontend Developer

#### Ukravtonomgaz

Ukravtonomgaz is a large-scale Ukrainian group operating in the liquefied gas market.

My Role:

I've participated in building the frontend of this website -

#### https://ukravtonomgaz.ua/

**Required skills:** Javascript, Flex, Twig, Gulp, PostgreSQL, jQuery slick-slider, Drupal CMS

Apr 2019 - Jan 2020

# React Native Mobile Developer

#### Hipcamp

Travel Booking application.

My Role:

- -build the Mobile UI
- -Enhance filtering function
- -Enhance Map service

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

# React Native Mobile Developer

#### Reelfolio

Reelfolio is the online social networking platform for the filmmakers.

#### My Role:

- -Developing mobile UI with React Native framework
- -Developing backend with NodeJS
- -Integrate backend and implement unit test
- -Deploying code to staging.production

Feb 2021 - Feb 2022

# React Native Mobile Developer

#### Marine snow

Marine snow is the premier global hall of songs, curated and contextualized.

#### My Role:

- -Mobile UI build of the Discovery part and onboarding logic implementation
- -Create the music orbs by using the lottie json
- -Optimize the codebase to reduce the memory and CPU usage
- -Gamification of the music play logic
- -Integrate backend api and unit test